{
  "id1": {
    "questions": [
      {
        "id": "1",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Who developed Python Programming Language?",
        "a": "Wick van Rossum",
        "b": "Rasmus Lerdorf",
        "c": "Guido van Rossum",
        "d": "Niene Stom",
        "answer": "c,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "2",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Who developed Python Programming Language?",
        "a": "Wick van Rossum",
        "b": "Rasmus Lerdorf",
        "c": "Guido van Rossum",
        "d": "Niene Stom",
        "answer": "c,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "3",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Who developed Python Programming Language?",
        "a": "Wick van Rossum",
        "b": "Rasmus Lerdorf",
        "c": "Guido van Rossum",
        "d": "Niene Stom",
        "answer": "c,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "4",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Who developed Python Programming Language?",
        "a": "Wick van Rossum",
        "b": "Rasmus Lerdorf",
        "c": "Guido van Rossum",
        "d": "Niene Stom",
        "answer": "c,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "5",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Who developed Python Programming Language?",
        "a": "Wick van Rossum",
        "b": "Rasmus Lerdorf",
        "c": "Guido van Rossum",
        "d": "Niene Stom",
        "answer": "c,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "6",
        "type": "2",
        "question": "Python file extension",
        "a": ".py",
        "b": ".ptx",
        "c": ".pn",
        "d": ".pth",
        "answer": "a,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "7",
        "type": "2",
        "question": "Python file extension",
        "a": ".py",
        "b": ".ptx",
        "c": ".pnt",
        "d": ".pth",
        "answer": "a,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      }
    ],
    "lesson": [
      {
        "title": "what is Java?",
        "type": "1",
        "description": "Our core Java programming tutorial is designed for students and working professionals. Java is an object-oriented, class-based, concurrent, secured and general-purpose computer-programming language. It is a widely used robust technology."
      },
      {
        "title": "History of Java",
        "type": "1",
        "description": "The history of Java is very interesting. Java was originally designed for interactive television, but it was too advanced technology for the digital cable television industry at the time. The history of Java starts with the Green Team. Java team members (also known as Green Team), initiated this project to develop a language for digital devices such as set-top boxes, televisions, etc. However, it was best suited for internet programming. Later, Java technology was incorporated by Netscape."
      },
      {
        "title": "Features of Java",
        "type": "1",
        "description": "The primary objective of Java programming language creation was to make it portable, simple and secure programming language. Apart from this, there are also some excellent features which play an important role in the popularity of this language. The features of Java are also known as Java buzzwords."
      },
      {
        "title": "Java if else",
        "type": "1",
        "description": "The Java if statement is used to test the condition. It checks boolean condition: true or false. There are various types of if statement in Java."
      },
      {
        "title": "Java switch case",
        "type": "1",
        "description": "The Java switch statement executes one statement from multiple conditions. It is like if-else-if ladder statement. The switch statement works with byte, short, int, long, enum types, String and some wrapper types like Byte, Short, Int, and Long. Since Java 7, you can use strings in the switch statement.In other words, the switch statement tests the equality of a variable against multiple values."
      },
      {
        "title": "Java switch case",
        "type": "2",
        "description": "The Java switch statement executes one statement from multiple conditions. It is like if-else-if ladder statement. The switch statement works with byte, short, int, long, enum types, String and some wrapper types like Byte, Short, Int, and Long. Since Java 7, you can use strings in the switch statement.In other words, the switch statement tests the equality of a variable against multiple values."
      },
      {
        "title": "Java switch case",
        "type": "2",
        "description": "The Java switch statement executes one statement from multiple conditions. It is like if-else-if ladder statement. The switch statement works with byte, short, int, long, enum types, String and some wrapper types like Byte, Short, Int, and Long. Since Java 7, you can use strings in the switch statement.In other words, the switch statement tests the equality of a variable against multiple values."
      },
      {
        "title": "Java switch case",
        "type": "2",
        "description": "The Java switch statement executes one statement from multiple conditions. It is like if-else-if ladder statement. The switch statement works with byte, short, int, long, enum types, String and some wrapper types like Byte, Short, Int, and Long. Since Java 7, you can use strings in the switch statement.In other words, the switch statement tests the equality of a variable against multiple values."
      }
    ]
  },
  "id2": {
    "questions": [
      {
        "id": "1",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Who invented Java Programming?",
        "a": "Guido van Rossum",
        "b": "James Gosling",
        "c": "Dennis Ritchie",
        "d": "Bjarne Stroustrup",
        "answer": "b,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "2",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Which component is used to compile?",
        "a": "JRE",
        "b": " JIT",
        "c": " JDK",
        "d": "JVM",
        "answer": "c,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "3",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Which one of the following is not a Java feature?",
        "a": "Object-oriented",
        "b": "Use of pointers",
        "c": "Portable",
        "d": "Dynamic and Extensible",
        "answer": "b,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "4",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Which of these cannot be used for a variable name in Java?",
        "a": "identifier & keyword",
        "b": "identifier",
        "c": "keyword",
        "d": "none of the mentioned",
        "answer": "c,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "5",
        "type": "2",
        "question": "Extension of java code",
        "a": ".js",
        "b": ".txt",
        "c": ".class",
        "d": ".java",
        "answer": "d,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "6",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Which environment variable is used to set the java path?",
        "a": "MAVEN_Path",
        "b": "JavaPATH",
        "c": "JAVA",
        "d": "JAVA_HOME",
        "answer": "d,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "7",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Which of the following is not an OOPS concept in Java?",
        "a": "Polymorphism",
        "b": "Inheritance",
        "c": "Compilation",
        "d": "Encapsulation",
        "answer": "c,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      }
    ],
    "lesson": [
      {
        "title": "what is Java?",
        "type": "1",
        "description": "Our core Java programming tutorial is designed for students and working professionals. Java is an object-oriented, class-based, concurrent, secured and general-purpose computer-programming language. It is a widely used robust technology."
      },
      {
        "title": "History of Java",
        "type": "1",
        "description": "The history of Java is very interesting. Java was originally designed for interactive television, but it was too advanced technology for the digital cable television industry at the time. The history of Java starts with the Green Team. Java team members (also known as Green Team), initiated this project to develop a language for digital devices such as set-top boxes, televisions, etc. However, it was best suited for internet programming. Later, Java technology was incorporated by Netscape."
      },
      {
        "title": "Features of Java",
        "type": "1",
        "description": "The primary objective of Java programming language creation was to make it portable, simple and secure programming language. Apart from this, there are also some excellent features which play an important role in the popularity of this language. The features of Java are also known as Java buzzwords."
      },
      {
        "title": "Java if else",
        "type": "1",
        "description": "The Java if statement is used to test the condition. It checks boolean condition: true or false. There are various types of if statement in Java."
      },
      {
        "title": "Java switch case",
        "type": "1",
        "description": "The Java switch statement executes one statement from multiple conditions. It is like if-else-if ladder statement. The switch statement works with byte, short, int, long, enum types, String and some wrapper types like Byte, Short, Int, and Long. Since Java 7, you can use strings in the switch statement.In other words, the switch statement tests the equality of a variable against multiple values."
      },
      {
        "title": "Java switch case",
        "type": "2",
        "description": "The Java switch statement executes one statement from multiple conditions. It is like if-else-if ladder statement. The switch statement works with byte, short, int, long, enum types, String and some wrapper types like Byte, Short, Int, and Long. Since Java 7, you can use strings in the switch statement.In other words, the switch statement tests the equality of a variable against multiple values."
      },
      {
        "title": "Java switch case",
        "type": "2",
        "description": "The Java switch statement executes one statement from multiple conditions. It is like if-else-if ladder statement. The switch statement works with byte, short, int, long, enum types, String and some wrapper types like Byte, Short, Int, and Long. Since Java 7, you can use strings in the switch statement.In other words, the switch statement tests the equality of a variable against multiple values."
      },
      {
        "title": "Java switch case",
        "type": "2",
        "description": "The Java switch statement executes one statement from multiple conditions. It is like if-else-if ladder statement. The switch statement works with byte, short, int, long, enum types, String and some wrapper types like Byte, Short, Int, and Long. Since Java 7, you can use strings in the switch statement.In other words, the switch statement tests the equality of a variable against multiple values."
      }
    ]
  },
  "id3": {
    "questions": [
      {
        "id": "1",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct identifier?",
        "a": "$var_name",
        "b": "VAR_123",
        "c": "varname@",
        "d": "None of the above",
        "answer": "b,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "2",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Which of the following is the address operator?",
        "a": "@",
        "b": " #",
        "c": " &",
        "d": "%",
        "answer": "c,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "3",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "C++ is a ___ type of language.",
        "a": "High-level Language",
        "b": "Low-level language",
        "c": "Middle-level language",
        "d": "None of the above",
        "answer": "c,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "4",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct syntax for declaring the array?",
        "a": "init array []",
        "b": "int array [5];",
        "c": "Array[5];",
        "d": "None of the above",
        "answer": "b,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "5",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Which of the following gives the 4th element of the array?",
        "a": "Array[0];",
        "b": "Array[0];",
        "c": "Array[3];",
        "d": "Array[1];",
        "answer": "c,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "6",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Array in C++ programming language?",
        "a": "None-contiguous",
        "b": "Contiguous",
        "c": "Both A and B",
        "d": "None",
        "answer": "a,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      },
      {
        "id": "7",
        "type": "1",
        "question": "Which types of arrays are always considered as linear arrays?",
        "a": "Single-dimensional",
        "b": "Multi-dimensional",
        "c": "Both A and B",
        "d": "Encapsulation",
        "answer": "1,",
        "explanation": "Python language is designed by a Dutch programmer Guido van Rossum in the Netherlands."
      }
    ],
    "lesson": [
      {
        "title": "what is a class?",
        "type": "1",
        "description": "A class in C++ can be defined as a collection of function and related data under a single name. It is a blueprint of objects. A C++ program can consist of any number of classes."
      },
      {
        "title": "Specify a class in C++?",
        "type": "1",
        "description": "By using the keyword class followed by identifier (name of class) you can specify the class in C++. Inside curly brackets, body of the class is defined. It is terminated by semi-colon in the end."
      },
      {
        "title": "Explain what is C++ objects?",
        "type": "1",
        "description": "Class gives blueprints for object, so basically an object is created from a class or in other words an object is an instance of a class. The data and functions are bundled together as a self-contained unit called an object. Here, in the example A and B is the Object."
      },
      {
        "title": "functions are classified?",
        "type": "1",
        "description": "In C++ functions are classified as\nReturn type\nFunction Name\nParameters\nFunction body"
      },
      {
        "title": "C++ switch case",
        "type": "1",
        "description": ""
      },
      {
        "title": "what is data abstraction?",
        "type": "2",
        "description": ""
      },
      {
        "title": "what is data encapsulation?",
        "type": "2",
        "description": ""
      },
      {
        "title": "types of Member Functions?",
        "type": "2",
        "description": ""
      }
    ]
  }


}